# Sufyan Saleem

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar

Website: https://sufyansaleem.netlify.app/ Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com Mobile: +923139243550

## **OBJECTIVE**

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Linknbit Software Engineer** Islamabad Pakistan Jan 2019 – present Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Websites, Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications. KYLA APP Jan 2019 - present Developed the backend in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, It is a Mobile App to know your laws Node mailer. Geolocation. Recommended actions Security for XSS and NOSQL Contact lawver with location and Injection details Paid and Unpaid Feature In Development **Dynasty Unleashed Models** Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers Deployment to Firebase & Users can register, create profile, add Google Play people and hire models at will Dokkani.co React/React-Native, Expo. Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Ecommerce Mobile App. Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, User can register, select products, Native Base

- add products to cart.
- User add products to wish list and checkout.
- Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.
- My Version

#### Yogurt App

Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate.

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo. **Native Base** 

#### **SmartsAid**

NGO App for refuges

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Elements

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

 Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2014 - 2018

Content Management Systems

Java, C#, MSSQL

Java

Gym - Point of Sale

PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

2010

RuneScape RPG

 Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you.

Portfolio Projects

#### DevCamper API

Bootcamps API

- One can register as a User or Publisher and login also.
- Publisher can create Bootcamps.
- Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations.
- Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture, and reset password.

HTML, NodeJS, Express, Mongoose,

MongoDB, Node mailer, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection, Docgen Postman

## **DevConnector**

- Social Media for developers where users register.
- Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them.

React, Redux, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku

### **SmartBrain**

- Smart Brain an app with face Recognition.
- Users can register, login and submit images via URL.
- The AI recognizes the face in the picture and draw a border around.
- It works only for one face in the image.

React, Redux, CSS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, Nodejs, Heroku, Netlify

## **EDUCATION**

#### BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

### F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

### 10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

## **SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE**

### **Specialities**

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

#### **Social Links**









### Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS Git, Heroku Rest, GraphQL, MVC Rust

Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

## **LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES**

#### Languages

English Urdu Pashto

#### **Hobbies**

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding,